National Coat & Suit Industry Recovery Board records 6036/010
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Coat & Suit Industry Recovery Board records
1918-1953
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Board
6036/010
2.33 cubic feet
2.33333333333333 linear ft.
Articles, reprints, pamphlets, correspondence, photographs.
This collection contains records, trial transcripts, and legal cases of the National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Board.
7528176
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 07, 2011
EAD encoding:
Kathryn Dowgiewicz, January 11, 2013
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).
Scope and Contents
Established by a vote of Congress on June 16, 1933, the National Industrial Recovery Act (NIRA) and its agency the National Recovery Administration (NRA), aimed to stimulate business recovery through industry wide codes. The over 500 codes affected about 22 million workers and those companies adhering to the codes were able to display the Blue Eagle label signifying compliance with the NRA. Following the demise of the NRA and its codes in May 1935, many of the employers in the coat and suit industry found the NRA codes and label an effective means to prevent aggressive competition within the industry. Eager to reinstitute a form of code and standards, the industry, working with the ILGWU, formed the National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Board to continue to seek fair trade and labor practices like its predecessor. The National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Board held its first meeting on June 16, 1936, and the Blue Eagle of the NRA was replaced by a new consumers' protection label, with the purpose remaining to inform consumers that the garment was made under fair working conditions. It was a countrywide industry body conducted under the joint auspices of management and labor to perpetuate, on a voluntary, self-governing basis, much of the structure and functioning of the machinery through which the field's Code of Fair Competition under the National Industrial Recovery Act had been administered.
The collection includes trial transcripts of Bernard Shapiro (Shapiro and Sons) against the Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit, and Skirt Manufacturers, Inc. from 1953. It includes multiple volumes, as well as memoranda and briefs, and the numbered items entered as exhibits for the case. Also contained in the collection are depositions, other legal cases involving the union or the American Cloak and Suit Manufacturers Association and Brooklyn Ladies' Garment Manufacturers Association, and the bound minute books of the Executive Committee of the Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers Protective Association.
The Executive Board Meeting Minutes and reports and resolutions of the National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Board from 1938 to the 1960s, as well as constitutions and by-laws, and financial statements, can be found in collection 6036/021 of the New York Suit and Coat Association Records.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/123: ILGWU. Research Department records 5780/020: ILGWU. New York Cloak Joint Board records 5915: National Coat & Suit Industry Recovery Board. Records, 1933-1972. 6167 mf: New York University. Tamiment Library, Collector. National Coat and Suit Recovery Board Documents, 1933-1972. Microfilm. 6036/021: New York Coat and Suit Association. Records.
Arrangement
National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Board (U.S.); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
7528176
- Series I. Legal cases, 1930-1953
  - Bernard Shapiro et al. v. Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers. Examination of Plaintiffs, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Volume 1. Pages 1-462.
  - Bernard Shapiro et al. v. Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers. Examination of Plaintiffs., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Volume 2. Pages 463-955.
  - Bernard Shapiro et al. v. Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers. Examination of Plaintiffs., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Volume 3. Pages 956-1438.
  - Bernard Shapiro et al. v. Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers. Examination of Plaintiffs., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Volume 4. Pages 1439-1870.
  - Bernard Shapiro et al. v. Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers. Examination of Plaintiffs., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Volume 5. Pages 1871-2325.
  - Bernard Shapiro et al. v. Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers. Examination of Plaintiffs., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Volume 6. Pages 2326-2756.
  - Bernard Shapiro et al. v. Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers. Examination of Plaintiffs., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Volume 7. Pages 2757-3181.
  - Bernard Shapiro et al. v. Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers. Memoranda and briefs, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bernard Shapiro et al. v. Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers. Memoranda and briefs, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bernard Shapiro et al. v. Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers. Exhibits, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Bernard Shapiro et al. v. Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers. Depositions, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Independent Association of Women's Manufacturers v. ILGWU, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Gerber v. Short (Boston coat and suit industry case), 1937 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - American Association of Cloak and Suit Manufacturers v. Merchants' Ladies' Garment Association, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Leonard Pace et al. v. American Cloak and Suit Manufacturers Association [Folder 1 of 2], 1933 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Leonard Pace et al. v. American Cloak and Suit Manufacturers Association [Folder 2 of 2], 1933 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - American Cloak and Suit Manufacturers Association v. Brooklyn Ladies' Garment Association, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn Ladies' Garment Association v. American Cloak and Suit Manufacturers Association [Folder 1 of 3], 1930 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn Ladies' Garment Association v. American Cloak and Suit Manufacturers Association [Folder 2 of 3], 1930 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn Ladies' Garment Association v. American Cloak and Suit Manufacturers Association [Folder 3 of 3], 1930 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Legal Decisions bearing on the collective agreements of the coat and suit industry (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Series II. Meeting minutes, 1918-1922
  - Minutes of the Executive Committee of The Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers Protective Association, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Bound volume
  - Minutes of the Executive Committee of The Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers Protective Association, 1920-1922 (Box 3, Folder 13)